JUNZE SHEN

Madrid, Spain | (+34) 671671705 | junze.shen@student.ie.edu | GitHub Profile | LinkedIn Profile

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Financial Analyst with demonstrated experience working in the Trust sector as an analyst. Skilled in Quantitative Finance, Al in Finance, and Financial Projection & Modelling. Currently pursuing an MSc in Finance with a specialization in Quantitative & Al Finance at IE Business School. CFA Level I candidate.

EDUCATION

IE BUSINESS SCHOOL MADRID, SPAIN

Masters in Finance – 8th Worldwide in FT

SEP. 2022 - Jul. 2023

- Current GPA: 3.6 / 4.0
- Key Subjects: Quantitative Finance (4.0/4.0), Fixed Income Derivatives (4.0/4.0), and AI in Finance (4.0/4.0)
- Key Projects: M&A Valuation—Apply & Disney, Pfizer Financial Statement Projection

BOSTON COLLEGE – 7th in Undergraduate Education (US News Rankings)

BOSTON, U.S.

Bachelor of Economics, Minor in Computer Science

Aug. 2018 - May. 2022

- Overall GPA: 3.59; Major GPA: 3.67
- Key Coursework: Machine Learning in Finance (4.0/4.0), Econometrics (3.67/4.0), Quantitative Investing (3.67/4.0)
- Conducted Projects: Dynamic Pair Trading using Kalman Filter, NBA Players Salary Prediction using ML.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ORIENT SECURITIES XIAN, CHINA.

Data Analyst in Single Funds Trust Service department

May. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Chinese Top Comprehensive Security Company with over \$320 billion assets under management

- Performed daily screenings of Chinese government municipal debt and corporate debt market.
- Spearheaded data analyses including filtering the interest rates and debt rating scores of the debt market to meet clients' preferences.
- Projected interest rates by Monte Carlo simulation using time-series algorithms, visualized the results, and presented to senior management.

BOSTON COLLEGE - INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON COURSE

Boston, U.S.

Teaching Assistant

Feb. 2020 – Dec. 2020

- Held a 1-hour weekly discussion session for students in the Computer Science course.
- Graded +40 assignments for students and provided assistance during office hours every week.
- Assisted professor with course materials preparation including exam and homework questions setting.

Personal Endeavour Madrid, Spain.

Corporation Bankruptcy Prediction Using AI

JAN. 2023 - JUNE. 2023

- Explored and mined +40000 companies' fundamental and stock data using API from FRED and Alpha Vantage.
- Arranged raw data into 28 attributions, 5-year data per company and performed data preprocessing including data rebalancing and normalization.
- Built 10 candidates prediction models ranging from CNN, LSTM, GRU, etc. and opted for the most predictive model with 1000 iterations on randomly selected test and train data to simulate the real-world scenario.
- Regularized the final prediction model (CNN) by using random dropout and obtained an overall accuracy of 85%.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

"PAPER-CUT" PHONE REPAIR CO.

XIAN, CHINA.

Volunteer

Jul. 2016 - Jun. 2017

Conducted user reviews focusing on the UI, PPI, Appearance, and Built-in app of newly released mobile phones.

OTHER INFORMATION & INTERESTS

Language: Chinese (Native), English (Bilingual), Japanese (B1 level)

IT Skills: Proficient in MS Excel, Power BI, Python, SQL (basic), R, MATLAB, Financial Modelling, Bloomberg (basic)

Achievements: 2nd place in 2019 National Chinese Guitar Contest